marco.org 2018-12-19

# Overcast

This policy applies to all information collected or submitted on Overcast’s website and our apps for iPhone and any other devices and platforms.

## Information we collect

When creating an account, you will be asked to enter an optional email address and a password. Email addresses are **only** used for logging in, password resets, responding to emails that you initiate, and notifications that you request. We don’t send promotional emails.

You may choose **not** to provide an email address and have an anonymous sync account instead.

We store information about your podcasts, episodes, and listening progress to sync this information between the website and your devices. We also collect anonymous statistics about which podcasts are most popular to help inform our recommendation engine.

### **Technical basics**

If you enable notifications, we must store a token to send them. We **never** use notifications for marketing.

If you upload files to Overcast, we need to store them until you delete them.

If you subscribe to a password-protected podcast, we need to store the credentials you provide in order to keep it updated.

We use cookies on the site and similar tokens in the app to keep you logged in. Our server software also stores basic technical information, such as your IP address.

### **Twitter accounts**

If you connect a Twitter account, episodes that you “recommend” may appear in Overcast to people who follow you on Twitter, identifying you as the recommender.

Any podcasts you add to Overcast may appear to your Twitter followers in their “Podcasts You Might Like” section.

We store a read-only Twitter login token to look up your Twitter username and avatar, and who you follow. Overcast cannot post tweets, change your account, or read your private messages. You can revoke access to your Twitter account at any time.

### **Ads and analytics**

Overcast’s app collects aggregate, anonymous statistics, such as the percentage of users who use particular features, to improve the app.

No personal data is used to target Overcast’s ads except the categories of podcasts that you’re subscribed to, such as “Technology” or “Business”. Each ad collects, and shares with its advertiser, only three numbers: total views, total taps, and total subscriptions from the ad.

## Information usage

We use the information we collect to operate and improve our website, apps, and customer support.

We do not share personal information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to accomplish Overcast’s functionality. We may share anonymous, aggregate statistics with outside parties, such as how many people listen to a particular podcast with Overcast.

We may disclose your information in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal requirements; to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud or abuse, violations of our policies; or to protect our rights and property.

In the future, we may sell to, buy, merge with, or partner with other businesses. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets.

## Security

We implement a variety of security measures to help keep your information secure. For instance, all communication with the app and website requires HTTPS with certificate pinning. Passwords are [hashed](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographic_hash_function), not stored, using industry-standard methods (currently [bcrypt](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt)).

## Accessing, changing, or deleting your information

You may access or change your information or delete your account from the Overcast iOS app.

Deleted information may be kept in backups for up to 90 days. Backups are encrypted and are only accessed if needed for disaster recovery.

## Third-party links and content

Overcast displays links and content from third-party podcast feeds and sites, and downloads podcast files directly from each podcast’s third-party servers. These have their own independent privacy policies, and we have no responsibility or liability for their content or activities.

## California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We comply with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

## Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

## Information for European Union Customers

By using Overcast and providing your information, you authorize us to collect, use, and store your information outside of the European Union.

## International Transfers of Information

Information may be processed, stored, and used outside of the country in which you are located. Data privacy laws vary across jurisdictions, and different laws may be applicable to your data depending on where it is processed, stored, or used.

## Your Consent

By using our site or apps, you consent to our privacy policy.

## Contacting Us

If you have questions regarding this privacy policy, you may email [privacy@overcast.fm](mailto:privacy@overcast.fm). Please note that account deletion should be done within the Overcast app, not via email requests, for security reasons.

## Changes to this policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page. Summary of changes so far:

  * **July 16, 2014:** First published.
  * **February 26, 2016:** Added Fabric crash reporting and analytics.
  * **September 6, 2016:** Added premium subscriptions and ads; reorganized analytics.
  * **February 20, 2017:** Removed third-party analytics and ads; other minor edits.
  * **February 28, 2017:** Added EU and international-transfer sections.
  * **March 13, 2018:** Added password-protected podcast support.
  * **March 16, 2018:** Edited various sections for clarity and brevity.
